Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series I; 4.2 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, I.A
    - Yale University Music Library
      See the Correspondence file in the Music Library's Archival Reference file
    - Yamamoto, K.
    - ?, Adell, 1942 Nov. 12; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 234)
      In form of a poem
  - Requests for Information from Monique Leduc, I.B
    - Chylínska, Teresa (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1986 Apr.-June. -- 3 items from Chylínska (typed letter signed (photocopy) from E. Robert Schmitz to Karol Szymanovski enclosed)
      no date. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Duparfait, Claude (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1984 Feb. 8. -- 1 item from Duparfait
      1984 Feb. 24. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Elliot, Paula (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1989 Oct. 27. -- 1 item from Elliot
      1989 Dec. 3. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Francesconi, Gino (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1989 Nov. 26. -- 1 item from Francesconi
      1989 Dec. 20. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Kirkpatrick, John, 1966-1970; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 235)
      His "Tentative list of Ives-Schmitz correspondence etc. among Ives's paper" enclosed ([2] sheets; 28 cm. typescript)
    - Kozar, John (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1984 Dec. 7. -- 5 items from Kozar (4 enclosures)
      1985 Jan. 3. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Nichols, Roger (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1984-1986. -- 2 items from Nichols
      1984-1986. -- 2 items from Monique Leduc
    - Orenstein, Arbie (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1982 Aug.-Oct. -- 2 items from Orenstein
      1982 Sep. 15. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Samuel, Harold
      See: Yale University Music Library. Archives reference file
    - Suchoff, Benjamin (Box 9, Folder 235)
      1978 Aug.-Sep. -- 4 items from Suchoff ( 2 enclosures)
      1978 Sep. 6. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Weinstein, Larry (Box 9, Folder 235)
      ca. 1987. -- 2 items Script outline and budget for television program, Ravel (37 p., bound; 28 cm. typescript) and business card of Larry Weinstein of Rhombus Media Inc.
      1987 Jan. 29. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Wiecki, Ron, 1991 May 12; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 235)
      From Monique Leduc (photocopy)
    - Unidentified fragment of autograph letter signed in Italian with Bologna on letterhead, [ca. 1927?]; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 235)
- Music, 1913-1947; Series II; 1.7' (4 boxes)
  This series includes holograph, manuscript, and published music by Schmitz and others. It is arranged alphabetically by composer, and then by title. Uniform titles are used to bring together all of the manifestations of a work with different titles.
  - Barraud, Henry, 1900-
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra; arranged] Concerto: pour piano et orchestre / Henry Barraud. -- [1946]., 1 manuscript piano score (66 p.); 33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
      Holograph, signed, in ink with pencil additions.
      Accompaniment arranged for piano.
      Publisher's copy.
      Publisher from stamp on page 2: Lucien de Lacour, Paris
      Note on page 2: Property of E. Robert Schmitz 3508 Clay Street San Francisco California
      Spiral-bound positive and negative photocopies with different markings laid in.
  - Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951
    - [Diversions. II], [3] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Holograph in ink.
      For piano.
      Composed 1922.
      "Carpenter" in pencil on page 1.
    - Little Nigger / JAC. -- 1916 Apr. 20., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Holograph signed, in ink.
  - Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947
    - [Pezzi, string quartet, op. 34. Fox-trot; arranged] Fox-Trot / Alfredo Casella. -- 1920., [8] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Arranged for piano, 4 hands?
      Primo part only.
  - Castro, José María, 1924-1964
    - Sonata de Primavera: para Piano / José María Castro. -- 1939., 28 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil additions.
      At end of each movement: Enero 28-Feb. 20. -- Junio 17-1939. -- José Maria Castro. B--os Aires Julio 21-1939.
      On title page: Return to A. Copland Hotel Empire N.Y.C.
  - Chávez, Carlos, 1899-
    - [Otros tres exágonos] Exáganos / musica de Carlos Chávez; poema de Carlos Pellicer. -- 1924., 1 manuscript score ([14] p.); 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil and red ink additions.
      For soprano or tenor, flute, oboe, bassoon, flute, viola, and piano.
      On title page and last page: Carlos Chávez México 1924.
      On 2nd title page: Carlos Chávez 5 Minetta Street New York City; and ...dedicada a Edgar Varèse.
      Printed sheet with texts laid in.
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 3] Carlos Chávez. -- 1928 Jan.-Feb., [21] sheets of music; 39 cm. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Holograph signed (photocopy).
      At end: N.Y. enero - febrero 1928 Carlos Chávez.
      On bottom of first page: Addresses = in Mexico City from June 1928 to December 928 [sic] 29 Salamanca 40 in New York City = 5 Minetta Street.
  - Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849
    - [Etudes, piano] E. Robert Schmitz' Edition of the Chopin Etudes. -- New York: Carl Fischer, c1938, 174 p. of music, bound; 31 cm. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Publisher's number: N.87-119
      Contains pencil markings.
  - Cliquet-Pleyel, Henri, 1894-1963
    - Shimmy: pour piano / Henri Cliquet-Pleyel. -- 1922., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Holograph, signed, in ink.
      At end: 3 décembre 1922 Henri Cliquet-Pleyel.
      On title page: Pour Robert Schmitz.
  - Componimenti Diversi
    - Componimenti Diversi: Balletti e Correnti..., 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Manuscript in ink
      Includes: violino primo, violino secondo, viola, and basso
      Photocopies of published music laid in: Balletto Terzo, Balletto, Corrente, Balletto Quarto / Plate number: 109141-64
  - Cory, George C., Jr.
    - [Sonatina, piano] Sonatina: for piano / by George Cory. -- 1947-1948., 16 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Manuscript [?] (photocopy).
      Label on front cover: Reproduced and bound by Independent Music Publishers New York City.
  - Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965
    - Maestoso. -- [1926]., 8 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy).
      Groves: movement 3 of Sinfonietta, Chamber orchestra, 1928.
    - One moment, please! / Henry Cowell. -- 1926., [1] sheet of music; 33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Holograph (photocopy).
      In top left corner: For Armitt Brown Christmas 1926.
  - Danz, Louis
    - Traffic: a satire / By Louis Danz., 9 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Holograph in ink with pencil additions.
      On title page: written for and to E. Robert Schmitz.
  - Fontaine, Louis [?]
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 1] Sonata #1 / Louis [?] Fontaine., XVII sheets of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Holograph [?], signed (photocopy).
      On page I: á Louise Pelletier.
  - Fontenay, Roger de
    - À chenet Ellébente / ? de Fontenay; ?. -- 1913, 1 manuscript score (8 p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Nov.
      Holograph [?], signed, in ink with blue pencil corrections.
      For voice, oboe, 2 violins, viola, violoncello, cymbals, and piano.
    - Elle avait trois couronnes d'or... / Musique de Roger de Fontenay; Poésie de Maeterlinck., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
      For voice and piano.
    - Elle l'enchaîna dans une grotte; R. de Fontenay; M. Maeterlinck. -- 1914 Mar. 3., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Holograph [?], signed, in ink.
      For chorus (SATB).
      On page 1: Paris 3 Mars 1914.
    - Les filles aux yeux baudés / R. de Fontenay; M. Maeterlinck. -- 1913 Nov., 1 manuscript score ( [2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Le Maître des Songes / R. de Fontenay; ? Fleg ?. -- 1913 Nov. 22., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Holograph [?], signed, in ink with pencil additions.
  - Freeman, M.C.
    - Rhapsodie I / M.C. Freeman., [8] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Holograph [?] in pencil.
  - Hammond, Richard
    - A Persian Life / Music by Richard Hammond; The Dance Poems of Armenter-Ohánian by Edwin Evans: for soprano and chamber orchestra. -- 1923 Nov.-Dec., 1 manuscript score (81 p.); 31 cm. (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Holograph [?], signed, in pencil.
      On title page: Written for and dedicated to Miss Greta Torpadie.
      At end: November December 1923 (Dec. 31st).
  - Harsányi, Tibor, 1898-1954
    - [Concertino, piano, string quartet] Concertino: pour piano et quator à cordes / Tibor Harsányi., 1 manuscript score (1 p.) + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 19)
      Holograph in ink with red pencil and ink additions and manuscript in ink (parts).
      Page 1 of score only.
      Includes string parts.
      Pencil notes on title page.
  - Hauer, Josef Matthias, 1883-1959
    - Atonale Musik: Klavierstücke: 1922 / Josef Matthias Hauer. -- Berlin: Schlesinger'sche Buch. -u. Musikhandlung Rob. Lienau, c1923., 2 volumes of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 20)
      Plate numbers: s.10182 I-II.
  - Haussermann, John (William, Jr.)
    - [Rhapsodic Overture] Rhapsodic Overture: for piano and orchestra: opus 17 / John Haussermann. -- [1939-1940]., 1 manuscript score (67 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 21)
      On title page: Boosey-Hawkes...
      Duration: 10 to 11 min.
    - [Rhapsodic Overture; arranged] Rhapsodic Overture: opus 17: arranged for two pianos / John Haussermann. -- [1939-1940]., 1 manuscript score (24 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955
    - Chant de joie: pour Orchestre / A Honegger. -- 1923 Jan., 1 manuscript score ([29] p.); 45 cm. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Holograph, signed, in ink with blue and red pencil additions.
      At end: Paris Janvier 1923.
      On title page verso in Arthur Honegger's hand: à Germaine Schmitz en souvenir de nos essais de flirt americain restés hélas! sans résultats.
      Above title on page 1: Maurice Ravel.
      Stamp on 1st and last pages: Société des Auteurs... 22 Fev 1923 263,089 10, Rue Chaptal Paris.
  - Illiashenko, Andre
    - Deux danses en forme de variations: pour piano / Andre Illiashenko. -- Paris: Éditions Maurice Senart, c1930., 8 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 23)
      Plate number: E.M.S.7976.
      Cover signed by composer.
  - Jacobi, Frederick, 1891-1952
    - Burleschi / Frederick Jacobi., 6 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Manuscript (photocopy) [title page holograph in ink?].
    - Three Preludes / Frederick Jacobi. -- 1921., 2, [3], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Manuscript (photocopies) [title page holograph in ink?].
      Inscription above title of Prelude no. 3: To Victor Wittgenstein.
  - Johnson, Lockrem, 1924-1977
    - [Etudes, piano, op. 18] Three Etudes: op. 18 / Lockrem Johnson. -- c1946 Oct. 13., 10 p. of music; 39 cm. (Box 11, Folder 25)
      Holograph [?] (photocopy).
      At end: April 9, 1946.
      On page 1: To Mme. Berthe Poncy-Jacobson.
      Pencil note on title page: Lent to Adeline Foreman Tacoma.
    - [Sonatas, piano, op. 19A, no. 2] Second Sonata: op. 19A: for piano / Lockrem Johnson. -- c1946 Nov, 5, c1947 Mar. 17., 15 p. of music; 39 cm. (Box 11, Folder 25)
      At end: 1946 Nov. 25.
      On page 1: To Mrs. Edgar Ames.
    - [Sonatas, piano, op. 24, no. 4] Fourth Sonata: op. 24 / Lockrem Johnson. -- 1947 Aug. 10., 16 p. of music; 39 cm. (Box 11, Folder 25)
      At end: 1947 July 3.
      On page 1: To Anne Macfarlaine.
      On title page: sent to Adeline Foreman Tacoma.
  - Koechlin, Raymond F.
    - [Capriccio, A major] Capriccio: Es dur / R. Koechlin., [4] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 26)
      Holograph(?) signed, in ink
    - [Klavierstücke, no. 4] Klavierstück: No. 4 / R. Koechlin, [8] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 26)
      On first page in pencil pointing to signature: Ch. Koechlin
    - [Variations, piano] Twelve variations: for piano / by R.F. Koechlin. -- 1925., [10] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 27)
      Holograph(?) in ink with pencil additions.
      3 manuscript parts from an arrangement(?) laid in.
    - 12 Variations on an Irish Theme: for Full Orchestra: op. 27 / R. Koechlin. -- 1926, 1 manuscript score (29 p.) + 52 parts; 32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 28)
      Holograph(?) signed, in ink with pencil additions, parts manuscript and ink, pencil, and copies.
      On title page: Respectfully dedicated to Mr. E.W. Ehrnam
    - Unidentified piano work, song, sketches, and parts found in the folder with the piano variations (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - [Sketches], [9] p. of music; 22-31 cm. (Box 11, Folder 29)
        Holograph(?) in pencil.
      - [Sketches], 17 parts; 20-32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 29)
        Manuscript and holograph(?) in ink and pencil
      - [Sketches], [8] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 29)
        Holograph(?) in ink.
      - [Un coq qui chante...], 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - [Un coq qui chante...], 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 33 cm. (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Luening, Otto, 1900-
    - [Intermezzi, piano. Stars] Stars / Otto Luening., [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - [Sonatas, piano ([undated])] Sonata for Piano / Otto Luening., 10 sheets of music; 32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 30)
      Unable to find in worklists.
  - Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974
    - [Etudes, piano, orchestra] Cinq Études: pour piano et orchestre / Darius Milhaud. -- 1920., 1 manuscript score (47 p.) + 1 part (12 p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 31)
      On title page of score: I Vif. -- II Doucement. -- III Fugues. -- IV Sombre. -- V Romantique.
      Note signed by Milhaud on title page verso.
      On bottom of page 1 of score: Copenhagen 20 Juin 1923.
      At end of 1st etude: pour Robert Schmitz.
      At end of 2nd etude: pour Marcelle Meyer.
      At end of 3rd etude: pour Andrée Vaurabourg.
      At end of 4th etude: à la mémoíre de Juliette Merovitch.
      At end of score: pour Nininha [sp] Velloso-Guerra l'Enclos 12 Aout 1920.
      At end of part: Copenhague Join l'Enclos Auot 1920 pour Ninha Velloso-Guerra.
    - [Symphonies, no. 6] 6e Symphonie: quatuor vocal, hautbois, violoncelle / Milhaud. -- 1923., 1 manuscript score (15 p.) + 7 parts; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 32)
      Manuscript in ink, with pencil additions, title page holograph.
      On title page: 1er manuscrit -- à G.S.
      On title pages of 6 parts: à Germaine Schmitz.
    - [Symphonies, no. 6. Movements II-III (Sketches)], [7] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 33)
      Holograph in ink, some pages crossed out in blue pencil.
  - Parrish, Carl
    - [Fugue, piano, A minor] Fugue: A minor / Carl Parrish. -- 1928 June., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 10, D flat major] Premier Concerto: pour piano: Op. 10 / Serge Prokofiev., 1 manuscript score (92 p.); 38 cm. (Box 12, Folder 35)
      Manuscript in ink with pencil additions.
      Composed 1912.
  - Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1991
    - Four Tone Pictures / Wallingford Riegger., [6] p. of music; 23 cm. (Box 12, Folder 36)
      Op. 14.
      Composed 1932.
      Photocopy glued to music paper.
      On front title, signature, and address, in Wallingford Riegger's hand[?].
  - Salzedo, Carlos, 1885-1961
    - Prelude to Olaf Bolm / [Carlos Salzedo]. -- [1920 July 8]., [3] manuscript p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 37)
      Holograph in ink and colored pencil.
      At end: Carlos Salzedo Seal Harbor Maine July 8 1920.
      Sheet with notes in ink about Salzedo and Bolm laid in.
  - Schmitz, E. Robert (Elie Robert), 1889-1949
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7] Concerto: No. 1: In 7 moods & 3 mouvements: piano + orchestre / E. Robert Schmitz., 1 manuscript score (143 p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Holograph, signed, in pencil, ink, and red pencil.
      Piano part in ink.
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7] Concerto: op. 7: In 7 moods + 3 movements / E. Robert Schmitz., 1 manuscript score (96 p.), bound; 44 cm. (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with red and blue pencil additions.
      Note glued to front cover verso and 3 notes laid in.
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7; arranged], 1 manuscript piano score (65 p.); 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Holograph in ink with red and blue pencil additions.
      Notes on discarded folder: Concerto (playback) le meilleur a mon sens le 2nd meilleur je le donne a Monique (1954) Il y a un 3me set que je garde qui est bon aussi-.
      Notes on discarded folder: Piano score avec changements mortie [sp] manuscrit Robert partie moi (Germaine Schmitz) / Priscilla Chang 901 California GA1-3854 Thursday at 2.
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7; arranged], 1 manuscript piano score (65 p.); 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Holograph in ink with pencil and red pencil additions.
      Note on discarded folder: See 2nd note above.
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7. Adagio; Arranged (Sketches)], [6] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Holograph in ink and pencil.
      1st page labelled "Andante."
    - [Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 7. Lento; arranged (Sketches)] Concerto: 1st Mvt: Orchestral reduction., [16] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Evolving Melodies: Piston's Counter. - July 24., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Holograph in pencil.
      Includes page numbers of exercises from Piston's Counterpoint.
      See also: unidentified piano quintet at the end of this series
  - Tansman, Alexandre, 1897-
    - [Bagatelles, piano] Deux Bagatelles: pour Piano / Alexandre Tansman., [4] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 12, Folder 40)
      On page 1: à Béla Bartók.
      At end: Manuscrit pour Robert Schmitz.
    - [Etude-Scherzo, piano] I.: Etude-Scherzo / Alexandre Tansman., [2] p. of music; 27 x 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 41)
      On 1st page: à Arthur Rubinstein.
      On bottom of 1st page: Tous droits reservés.
      With: Trois Études Transcendantes, and Impromptu N3.
    - [Études transcendantes, piano] Trois Études Transcendantes / Alexandre Tansman., [4] p. of music; 27 x 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 41)
      Dedications for each etude: I - à R. Mattrica. -- II - à Yanza [sp] Guller. -- III - à Ernest Levy.
      With: I. Etude-Scherzo; and Impromptu N3
    - [Impromptus, piano, no. 1] Impromptu: N1 / Al. Tansman., [2] p. of music; 27 x 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 41)
      Under title: (Extrait des "Impromptus").
      With: Nocturnes (Huit pièces lentes).
    - [Impromptus, piano, no. 3] Impromptu: N3., [1] p. of music; 27 x 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 41)
      With: I. Etude-Scherzo; and Trois Etudes Transcendantes.
      Under title: (extrait des "Impromptus").
    - [Nocturnes, piano. Selections] Nocturnes: (Huit pièces lentes) / Al. Tansman., [3] p. of music; 27 x 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 41)
      Includes: II, V, I, VII.
      With: Impromptu N1.
    - [Suites, pianos (2), orchestra; arranged] Suite: pour deux pianos avec accompagnement d'orchestre / Alexandre Tansman., 1 manuscript score (41 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 42)
      Orchestra accompaniment arranged for third piano.
      Third piano part laid in.
      On title page: à Robert Schmitz.
      On bottom of 1st page of part: Les accidents sont marqués pour chaque main séparément.
      Composed 1928.
  - Whithorne, Emerson
    - Mission San Juan Capistrano: Op. 52: no. 1 / Emerson Whithorne. -- [1930 Nov. 4]., 12 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 43)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy) with pencil additions.
      At end: Castle Argyle 4 - November 1930 Hollywood, California Emerson Whithorne.
  - Unidentified piano works:
    - No. 4: Rondo, [3] p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 12, Folder 44)
      Manuscript in ink with pencil and red pencil additions.
    - Choral: Wer nur den Lieben Gott läszt Walten, [1] sheet of music; 23 x 26 cm. (Box 12, Folder 44)
      Manuscript in ink with red pencil additions.
    - Unidentified piano quintet, 1 manuscript score (pp. 2-41); 28 cm. (Box 12, Folder 44)
      Holograph? in ink with pencil, red pencil, and red ink markings.
      In three movements: 1. ?; 2. Adagio; and 3. Presto.
      At end: Paris Avril-Sept. 1931
      Originally with Milhaud music; possibly by Schmitz in his hand?
      First page missing.
- Photographs, Series III; .8' (2 boxes)
  This series includes photographs, negatives, portraits, and caricatures of Schmitz and others. The photographs are arranged alphabetically. When more than one person appears in a photograph, a cross-reference has been made from the person or persons to the main entry. A pencil note appears on photographs which were originally found with the disassembled scrapbooks. Inscriptions are noted in the register.
  - Albert, King of Belgium, 1928 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Inscribed to Captain Prevost
    See also: Prevost, Arthur
  - Ambert, ?, 1912 July 28; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Antal, Jeno
    See: Schmitz, E. Robert
  - Arrau, Claudio
    See also: Torpadie, Greta
  - Bando, Mrs. Mitsumi, Mrs. Kyoko Yoshido, and 2 others, ca. 1932; 4 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Members of a trio that toured for Pro-Musica in 1932
  - Barrère, ?
  - Barrymore, John
  - Bartók, Béla (Box 13, Folder 2)
    1928 Jan. 2. -- 1 item, inscribed to Germaine Schmitz, New York (negative)
    no date. -- 1 item, with Joseph Szigeti, Davos, Switzerland
  - Beckhard, ?
    See: Royal Belgian Band
  - Belaiev, Viktor, 1927 Feb. 28; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, negative laid in
  - Bliss, Arthur
    See: Schmitz, E. Robert, and Torpadie, Greta
  - Boyce-Smith, Mrs.
  - Busoni, Ferrucci, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Photograph of portrait by Burkard
  - Calvocoressi, Michel D., 1913; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz
  - Casella, Alfredo, no date; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Includes photograph of portrait
  - Chaliapine, Fyodor Ivanovich
    See: Laberge, Bernard
  - Chávez, Carlos, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Photograph by Sherril Schell
  - Courboin, Charles M., no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Debussy, Claude, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Delaquerrière, José
    See: Torpadie, Greta
  - Diémer, Louis, 1910; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Photograph of bust, inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz
  - Eames, Emma, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, photograph by Falk, N.Y., c1892
  - Eichheim, Henry, 1931 Feb.; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz, Santa Barbara, negative laid in.
  - Fairbanks, Douglas
  - Golschmann, Vladimir, 1934 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Inscribed to Germaine Schmitz, St. Louis, photograph by Todd, St. Louis
    See also: Schmitz, E. Robert
  - Grechaninov, Alexsandr Takhonovich, 1864-1956, 1929; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Inscribed to Germaine Schmitz, negative laid in
  - Haas, Robert
    See: Pro Arte Quartet
  - Halleaux, Laurent
  - Hammond, Richard (Dick)
  - Hart, Violet
  - Honegger, Arthur (Box 13, Folder 6)
    1929. -- 2 items, with Ely Jade and Beth Jenny? Aboard the Rochambeau, N.Y., negative laid in
    1920. -- 1 item, photograph of portrait by Ochsé
    1949. -- 1 item
  - Indy, Vincent d'
  - Irish, Mrs.
  - Jade, Ely
    See: Honegger, Arthur
  - Jenny, Beth
  - Kochanski, Pawel ?
    See: Rubinstein, Artur
  - Koechlin, Charles, 1922 July 30; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Inscription to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz on back.
  - Koshetz, Nina D., 1929; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
    See also: Laberge, Bernard